There are many types of lusts in this world,
but the most fatal type is the one in which
both participants consider love till the end.
God is great.
Mahi.
Nooray, you people leave,
you inform Shah Jee that we have left,
we will call him when we get to Lahore.
Yes madam.
Once the trains comes,
we will leave too.
If you need anything else madam,
I will send it.
No you people leave.
Yes.
I will come.
What are you doing?
Look at that.
They have not left?
No, they are still…
Oh, its here.
What do you mean?
When someone comes late in the afternoon,
they won’t even get lunch?
Do you have some shame?
Tell me, where were you since morning?
Where have you been roaming?
Do you not care about your father’s old age?
That’s it, your emotional drama has started?
Yes, it has started.
No one says anything to you,
you do whatever you want with us.
He talks nonsense.
Fari.
Fari, please give me something to eat,
I am really hungry,
I swear I am starving.
Papa is here.
Your father is here, don’t say a word.
You have to stay quiet, you hear that?
I never say anything.
Be quiet.
Hello papa.
Hello.
Give it to me, I will keep it.
Hello papa.
Hello.
I am surprised,
you too are at home today?
Huh?
How are your exams going?
Did you prepare well?
I have worked really hard this time papa,
I have given all the exams till now
with a lot of preparation.
Yes, brother always prepares well,
the results comes out bad.
Shut your nonsense, okay?
I don’t have any high hopes from him.
Once he passes his BA,
I will get him a job as a clerk in my office,
what else can he do?
Did Sajjad call?
He had an interview in
the public service commission today.
Yes, the sister talked to him after the interview,
he was really happy and saying that
he will get the job by the will of God.
Yes, if God wills.
If God wills. Why not?
I only have hopes from my eldest son,
by the will of God he will do something good.
I will go check food.
Okay.
You are back.
Do you not have any work at home
apart from hanging around here?
What happened?
Why are you in a bad mood?
I feel uncle again…
Yes, make fun.
You too make fun.
No problem.
One day when I will become an affluent person,
you along with my father
will remain standing here.
God knows when that day will come,
It will take such a long time.
Go from here. Leave.
Why should I leave?
Its your time to leave.
This time your father will not
be able to tolerate your any failure.
Nothing like that will happen,
I am properly prepared this time.
Oh God, you will cheat.
Its really sad Feedi,
learn something from brother Sajjad.
Listen to me,
don’t give me these lectures.
Now leave from here,
I have to take out some important questions today.
Okay do call me,
I will help you in making
the cheating material.
Neighbors comes to rescue in hard times.
Brother, I think we will get late,
I also have to get the train to Lahore.
I don’t understand this adventure of yours,
Lahore is not even a forty minute flight,
but you need to waste your time in trains.
You feudal lords won’t understand
the romanticism of the train.
Do read “Orient Express” by Aghata Christie once,
then you too will be seen traveling in a train.
Leave it,
let me stay away from all this.
I already have enough
responsibilities of the home,
so this romanticism has no place in my life,
I will go pay my respect.
Try to come soon.
You are Sajawal’s son, right?
Yes.
What do you want old man?
What can you give?
If you want something, ask me.
I don’t want anything, I have everything.
No one has everything.
Something always lacks.
Really?
Then, please pray that
the train to Lahore gets late,
because brother is inside and
I think he will get me late.
If you miss the train, then let it happen.
Don’t travel today
or else you will lose everything,
whatever that you have and…
Hey, no, no
I am going to Lahore for a really important meeting,
if I don’t go everything will go wrong.
Everything will go wrong anyway.
Okay, it’s up to you,
if you want it like that.
From today your journey will begin,
no one knows where it will end.
No one knows.
What happened?
Shall we go?
You are back! Let’s go.
Where are you going
so late at night, brother?
If papa finds out,
you will get scolded badly.
And you have your exam in the morning too.
It’s necessary for me to go,
if he asks where I am, please handle it.
I will be back soon.
Brother, will you get us killed?
You know papa regularly comes once
at night to check on brother Sajjad.
Man, Feedi, she is right, it is really late,
you go in the morning.
Why don’t you people understand?
It’s necessary for me to go,
if I don’t go, everything will go wrong.
You people please handle it.
Brother…
Sajjad lock the door before you sleep.
Where is Fariha?
Papa…you?
What are you doing here?
Your mother is calling you downstairs, go.
Yes papa, I was going downstairs.
Yes, go.
Look at this,
this lazy man is still sleeping.
Wake him up,
he has an exam in the morning,
he is dreaming away.
Hey, Farhad.
Farhad.
Papa. Papa. Your medication.
I forgot to give it to you on my way up,
so I thought I would bring it.
You missed it yesterday, have it.
Or else you will get unwell.
I think your mother was calling Fariha for this.
Papa, you go I will come,
brother Farhad told us to wake him up at 12,
I will get fresh and study.
Its 12.
Wake him.
Wake him up, man!
He is still sleeping.
Yes, we are waking him.
Hey, Feedi, you almost got us killed today.
Hey, hero.
Where is Feedi, man?
That man must be coming too,
Babu Booti.
Not Babu Booti, its Baba Booti.
At least take his name correctly, idiot.
Hey don’t correct me when I am worried.
This is the limit.
Hey, Baba Booti is here on his ride.
But man, he looks like a private
detective from an old English movie.
Come on.
Where is Feedi?
I told him to come sharp at 12.
He must be on his way.
Look, I cannot stay here,
it’s really dangerous.
I have come secretly,
the board people have put spies after me.
Give me the money and
keep your cheating material.
Feedi has the money.
Damn it.
Police.
Raid.
Hey, I am dead.
I will be dead.
Come on. Move it.
Come on. Come on. Move it.
Okay Mr. Policeman,
we will meet soon,
take care of yourself.
Okay Mr. Inspector we will meet soon.
Remember what I told you.
Yes sir.
I will do it this time,
there is pressure from papa.
Next time I will surely study
and give the exam.
Yes fine, come on.
Okay, bye.
What happened?
Feedi, what is this drama?
What was this?
What happened?
The SHO was from the same locality,
he gave me a lift till here,
so what happened?
What was the SHO saying?
Nothing,
after all, we are really late,
we also need to get the guide too.
Where is he right now?
There he is. Come on.
Hey, hold my hand. Hold my hand.
Sister in law.
Sister in law,
can we go eat ice cream, please?
Not right now. Are you mad?
We will go in a little while.
Where is uncle?
I don’t see uncle, anywhere.
Bring it son, bring it, keep it here.
Careful brother.
See if we left anything.
There is nothing inside,
everything is here.
The black bag must be inside too, bring it.
Madam, everything is here, don’t worry.
How do I not worry, brother?
It’s my bag.
Sister in law it has my…
it has my jewelry.
Sister in law, I am telling you,
if he steals that I will choke him to death.
Listen, I will ruin you,
where did you keep my black bag,
tell me right now. I want it.
Calm down Maheen, we will find it.
Okay, if we don’t find it,
you will book me a flight right now
and I will go back.
Because what will I do without the bag?
Madam, maybe it’s inside,
I will just go now and look.
Wait, stop.
You think I am an idiot
that I let you go inside,
and then I wont get my bag or you!
Brother, you please send someone else
and get the things checked.
Hey Shaukay.
Shaukay come here.
Go and check in compartment five,
madam’s small suitcase is there, go see it.
Come soon.
You know you are an irresponsible porter,
in such a big train,
in so many compartments,
you only had to lose
my black bag in all these bags.
There is no bag inside.
You look for it yourself.
What?
Hey you picked the bag in front of my eyes,
how can it go anywhere?
Maheen, madam,
look at that, it looks like your bag,
it’s yours right?
It doesn’t look like my bag,
it is my bag.
Maheen.
Hey, listen. Stop. Give my bag.
This is what they call, face of a believer,
but actions of a sinner.
Are you not ashamed of
stealing someone’s bag?
Give it back.
What? What do you want?
My bag that you stole.
This is our luggage but this…
Yes, this is mine.
The thief gets caught in the end.
Actually, this is our luggage,
but I am sure you are mistaken.
Do you think my bag has feet,
that walked with your luggage?
Are you not ashamed?
You don’t look like a thief…
Maheen…
I should hand you over to the police
then you will speak the truth.
Ma’am, you are getting upset for no reason,
these bags can get exchanged by mistake.
That’s it.
This the excuse a thief makes
when they get caught.
I have no fault in all this, you know,
I think the porter made a mistake.
I am letting you go right now
because I don’t have time.
If I had time, I would have
handed you over to the police.
He is a thief, it had all my jewelry in it.
The way I am finding these pages,
I hope I find the answers to
the questions too, it will be great.
Please help me pass this time.
In the name of God…
Fari,
boil six eggs,
I am coming down.
What is all this that you are doing brother?
Can you not see,
I am preparing for my exam.
What have you done to papa’s coat?
He doesn’t even use it now.
This is the limit brother.
Mama is thinking that her beloved son
is wearing his father’s coat to get
blessings out of his father’s love
but you have filled it with cheating material.
Little one,
don’t act like my aunt.
Now come on, leave from here,
before Mughal e Azam comes looking for you,
and sees all this.
Come on, leave from here.
Out. out. out.
Brother, if you had finally got the paper,
you should have memorized five questions.
Memorized it!
Did I do all this hard
work to memorize all this.
Come on, little one.
Come on before he comes.
Little one, leave.
This is left.
Feedi.
Oh God,
this boy is weird,
he never gives me his dirty clothes to wash,
I wash all the clothes daily, but no.
Oh God, he has done the same thing inside.
This is the limit. I am tired.
When their wives come they will get fine.
I am tired of this boy,
he has created a mess.
I will wash these,
rest I will check later what is this trouble.
This is Seth Nisar’s mansion, right?
Yes, this is the mansion.
Okay,
Mr. Nisar is the same one
who has a cement factory in Okara, right?
No sir, he does import export,
he has his own gardens and lands.
Okay, okay,
actually I am new in the city,
no one knows each other,
it’s so hard to find his address.
Sir, don’t you have his mobile number?
Brother, I made a mistake.
I don’t know
where I missed his mobile number.
Do you have an event at your home?
Yes, yes,
Mr. Nisar’s daughter is getting married in a few days,
we are preparing for that.
Okay. Okay.
May God give her a good future.
I am sorry I bothered you people,
I think I have come to the next lane,
I will go check in the next lane.
Thank you.
Yes, alright.
Fari,
hurry up, its really late,
I have to get to the office.
I am coming brother.
Let’s go.
Come on.
Mama.
Hey, you didn’t leave,
you had your exam today.
Yes, yes, I am preparing to leave for that,
I have my exam at 2 pm.
I kept papa’s brown coat there,
I cannot find it anywhere, come on, find it for me.
Hey, what is wrong with you?
Will you make me fall?
Have you gone mad?
You look like a joker in your father’s coat.
You don’t know, I have to do a lot right now,
I have to go prepare the desk in the hall.
Come on, help me find it.
Hey, what coat?
The same one, that is torn?
Yes, that one.
The one that doesn’t have
two buttons in the sleeve.
I just washed it,
I thought when it dries,
I will give it to the hawker and get plates and glasses,
there are no utensils at home.
You washed it?
Yes, I washed it.
What did you do, mama?
Oh God, mama my whole course was in it,
why did you wash it?
What is wrong with him?
He is saying weird things.
Fine, it will dry in an hour,
then wear it in the evening.
I am disappointed,
I think all your efforts for
the exams have gone to waste.
No need to be sarcastic.
I know how sorry and disappointed you,
jealous girl.
Why would I be jealous?
After all, would you have gotten
a gold medal in the locality in BA?
Getting a gold medal is nothing great
and you will see all these people
who get gold medals will work for me,
this is how you poor people think.
Poor people.
Poor people?
Yes, we are poor, you are affluent people,
you have a lot of factories.
These factories and these big salaries
are the problem of you poor people.
I don’t know what was that bad day
that you people came as our neighbors?
I have been hearing since childhood,
that Mr. Ramzan is building his home,
he is building his home,
make it already and leave from here.
Why do we leave? You leave.
There is not long before the clock strikes 2.
You wasted my time,
I have to buy the guide on the way.
Okay listen, go carefully,
this country and nation needs
young people like you.
I will teach you a lesson…
She is after me.
Saeen, they are a family from Bahawalpur,
they are staying at some Seth Nisar’s home,
they have their mansion in Defence.
It’s wedding of Seth’s daughter’s,
women from Bahawalpur
have come as guests.
Really?
Then it is easy to find out about her,
Bahawalpur is not that far from us.
Yes master,
what is the order for me now?
After the wedding,
they will surely go back to Bahawalpur,
Essa, you have to keep
your eyes on them secretly.
If you want, you can call two to four
more people from the locality for this work.
Yes, master.
Okay Essa,
brother Sikandar shouldn’t find out,
be careful.
You don’t worry,
he will not find out
and your work will be done too.
Perfect.
A thief has getting caught in his fate.
Go Bushra,
see the arrangement in the kitchen.
See papa,
she has just come here and
she is talking about leaving.
Thank God that I came.
If uncle hadn’t called
and insisted again and again,
it would have been impossible for me
and sister in law to come here like this.
You know, I have complaints with brother Kazim,
I am upset with him, why didn’t he come?
Aunty, he would have surely come,
at the last moment him and Shah Jee,
got busy with the case of an old land
and you know that appearing
before the court is important.
Okay, you people are here,
we have to have a lot of fun together.
Hey aunty, you don’t worry about fun,
you just warn your neighbors
to have their headphones ready
because there will be a lot
of noise in this home of yours.
A lot of noise!
Hey, where are you lost?
I have been waiting for you for an hour.
Yes, speak up, I am listening.
You can listen to us on the phone too,
what is the point of coming here?
So far.
I can bet and tell you he is here,
but his attention is not here.
Whether you agree or not,
he is still thinking about her,
did the train journey, start your love story?
Did my brother fall in love with someone?
Are you guys done?
Please make a plan.
Then come on, lets do something.
And what about you
people watching TV for so long,
and I was waiting for you.
What about that?
Hey, check it out,
they have so much peace on their face,
where do they get so much peace from?
I will die,
my father will kill me if I fail this time too.
I heard it and died.
Feedi, I didn’t prepare because of you,
I wish I had not listened to you.
You people are useless,
I had told you people to prepare a little,
if nothing else, you should have kept
the guide in your shirt or trouser.
Now all of you die.
What will we do now?
What now? Go home quietly.
Yes, go home. You are right.
There is still an hour and
thirty minutes for the exam to end,
what will you say when you go home?
My love, no one will let us sit here.
Okay wait, I have an idea.
What?
Come on.
Come on. Come Feedi.
Hey come. Come.
I have told Nisar to keep all
the wedding functions in the lawn,
I don’t like guests who enter your rooms…
Bushra, why are you keeping the sweets here?
Go keep it in the kitchen.
This is the limit Bushra.
Getting these servant to work
will give me blood pressure.
What do I do? I don’t understand.
Hey, Bushra.
Bushra, go outside
and see the kid will fall.
Oh God. Go fast.
These servants will drive me mad,
I pray that the wedding goes smoothly, somehow.
By the will of God.
Has she reached or not?
Sister in law.
Fakeera.
Yes Mahi, I am here.
Sister in law,
I have looked through all my things,
but I cannot find my blue scarf.
Blue?
I had asked Fakeera to keep it myself.
Check properly, it must be there.
I have seen it ten times in all my things,
its not there.
Now tell me, what will I wear on the musical night,
I want to wear that blue dress, that’s it.
Fakeera.
Yes?
Did you keep my blue dress in my luggage?
Madam Mahi, madam had me
working on other things.
I was stitching the clothes,
she has sent fifty two dresses for madam Rida.
Fifty two dresses.
And your work after all
was being done by Asghari.
See sister in law, see,
she has ruined my celebration.
That’s it, its decided,
I will not sit in Rida’s musical night.
Oh Rida, what is wrong?
You have started creating
a scene as soon as you came.
Aunty, this always happens with me,
she has left half my clothes back.
Hey, you got so many clothes,
wear anything, why are you getting upset.
No,
I want to wear the same blue dress,
the scarf of which she left at home.
No problem,
you wear the scarf of my blue dress,
it matches your suit anyway.
You have not stopped being stubborn.
You are my friend, right?
You know about me, right?
When I think about something,
I don’t like if anything happens against it.
Mahi.
What is wrong, Mahi?
Why are you sad?
Okay, come on, get up.
We will go to the market
and get you a new scarf, okay?
Mahi, we will find it, come on, at least.
We will not find it.
It was an exact match.
I am telling you we will find it.
Come on, get up. Come on.
We will go.
Okay.
Fari.
Yes, papa?
Hey, I cannot find my blue colored file.
See if it is in the room.
Yes papa.
Hey brother Farhad, you are back.
You have a long life,
papa was just asking about you.
Its good he is back, come on,
quickly cook bread, he must be hungry too.
Yes mama.
Hello papa.
Hello.
Sit with us some time
and discuss something.
Come, sit.
How are your exams going?
Fine?
Look, I will not take anything less
than first division,
I need it at all cost.
Fine you are not as smart as your brother,
but you are the son of government superintendent,
Taufeeq Ahmad’s son,
so we need the first division.
Yes papa, I hope so, you pray.
Only prayers don’t help,
you have to work hard with all your heart.
Now there are two positions
open in my office for junior clerk,
I am thinking you pass your BA,
I will talk to them and request them
that I have worked there for thirty years,
they will care for that at least.
So I will get you a job in my office.
This will be good,
my son will be a big officer too.
You son, prepare hard for your CSS.
When you clear your CSS
my difficulties will be eased too.
Papa, why do you worry?
My preparation is complete,
I will fulfill your wish by the will of God.
Live long, live happy.
When you do your CSS,
a lot of my burden will be reduced.
Yes, by the will of God.
Serve food now.
Your beloved is here after wasting the day.
Yes, I am serving it.
Turn it on, turn on Geo for the news.
Yes.
Mrs. Arfah, who is this girl?
She has made the whole celebration lively.
Oh, your brother Nisar,
his best friend, Kazim Shah’s daughter.
She is Rida’s childhood friend.
When we used to live in Bahawalpur,
we used to visit their house often.
Now see, Mr. Shah and his wife couldn’t come
because of something important,
they sent their daughter and daughter in law.
You know, Rida had told me
that if my friend doesn’t come,
I will not talk to anyone.
No, no, no. hey, no, no, no.
No, please.
Yes, yes papa,
I am preparing a lot,
I won’t disappoint you.
Why are you jealous?
Now if papa has hopes from me,
I am sure he has something in his mind.
That’s it. Stop.
I know well what he would have in his mind.
You two are flatterer,
he is bootlicker number one and
this little one is bootlicker number two.
You keep on buttering him.
One day will come.
My day will also come.
I won’t even ask you two.
When will it come brother?
Yes, when you will work as
a junior clerk in papa’s office, right?
I don’t want to work as a clerk.
This is weird about papa,
the elder son does CSS and
the younger one works as a small time clerk.
Why?
I won’t do it, I will protest.
Yes, the seventeenth grade seat is vacant for you.
Those people are waiting since
so long that when Mr. Farhad will come.
You two wait, I will fix her today.
Yes,
you are here,
bootlicker number three.
Actually people with ordinary thinking,
ordinary people, their mind is
fixed on high positions and grades,
my destination is something else.
Yes, let us hear it, what is your destination.
I will tell you one day,
right now you and Fariha sit and
think about recipes for sauces and jams.
Do you see him.
Sallu is here,
I am leaving.
Take care of papa.
Brother, why are you leaving?
If papa finds out we will get scolded badly.
You handle him, after all,
you are an expert at flattering.
Brother…
Handle him. Okay, fine?
Do you see his actions?
Why do you bother my brother all the time?
Its my hobby.
Go make the sauce.
Yes brother, I did meet my friends.
What is the plan of coming back?
You know mama gets sad without you.
It will take a few more days brother,
a important task has come in the middle.
Important task?
What is the important task?
Is everything okay?
Yes, everything is fine.
Give my hello and love to mama
and tell her that I will come soon.
And tell her not make you call me
with excuses to find out how I am.
Fine, I will give her your message.
Okay, we will talk later.
Bye.
Sir, the guests are here.
Why are you smiling so much?
Faris messaged,
he is saying
I cannot spend this time without you.
Oh God, your husband’s love filled message.
Man, I think that this mobile is a great invention.
I mean,
calls,
messages,
you get to talk immediately.
I feel that some lover invented it,
whose ancestors must have
some lover type person,
whose lover would have given her
life by drowning in the sea
because she didn’t get the message on time.
You are the limit, Mahi,
you made a story out of something so trivial.
Just like that, give it a thought.
What are you doing?
Mahi.
Mahi, what are you doing?
I am not allowed to call him.
Papa has told me not to.
Not an issue, papa is not here.
Papa. Papa. See, he is not here.
Yeah, but I am not allowed to call him,
I have also told him not to.
Okay, just for fun.
It doesn’t look nice. Mahi, he is calling.
Give it to me. Mahi, give it to me.
No.
Nothing happens, its okay,
a little fun is allowed.
Man….
Hello.
Yes, hello.
Who are you?
Who do you want to talk to?
I am sorry I dialed the wrong number.
No, nothing like that,
now that you have dialed the number,
what will you lose talking to me for two minutes.
You know, you have an intoxicating voice.
What do they say in English?
Toxic.
Really? No one has told me this earlier.
Hey you must not have found someone
as appreciative as me, before.
What do you do?
First you tell me, who are you?
And what is your name?
Yes, my name is Suneela Jabeen.
People say that what’s in the work.
Suneela Jabeen, wow,
your name is equally intoxicating.
Faris, how dare you? You cheat!
How can you talk to my friend like this.
Oh Rida, you.
Shut up, Faris,
and don’t call me again, you cheat.
Hey, we can’t do that,
the wedding is fixed, we cannot leave him.
I am sorry, this was funny.
So Mr. Taufeeq, how are you?
I am good.
Are you coming from the office?
Yes, I got a little late today.
Mr. Taufeeq, I have told Naheed,
that after today no need to bring
the paper from Mr. Taufeeq’s home daily,
we are getting our own subscription.
The paper has been coming from our home
for the past twenty years,
so you can do it for two to four more years.
You know, neighbors help neighbors,
even if it is a newspaper worth ten rupees.
Oh yes, I remembered,
I met Mr. Affaq from education
board in the morning.
Yes, he is an examiner in
the education department, right?
Yes, the same one.
He was really complaining about Farhad.
What happened?
He is the external examiner
at Farhad’s exam center.
Yes.
He was saying that
he didn’t give any exam.
He was really feeling sorry,
that the son of such an educated
and capable father’s son is
so uneducated, so incapable.
He will surely fail this time too.
He was being sarcastic towards me
for giving me the newspaper for twenty years!
Where is he?
Sajjad has gone to see where he is,
he must be coming back with him.
Yes, he must be sitting with his loafer,
cheap friends, he must be playing something.
They are here.
Come son, come.
Where were you son?
Papa, I was here with friends.
Okay, nothing,
you had your last exam today,
so I wanted to ask about that,
how did it go?
It went well, I had worked hard.
Okay, okay.
Look, should we hope for a first division or
will you give us a bigger happiness than that?
Papa, I don’t know about first
or second division,
I have worked hard,
rest is in God’s hands.
Oh God.